Guide to the American Advertising Federation. Raleigh-Durham Records, 2003-2009 RL.00004
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
American Advertising Federation. Raleigh-Durham records
1988-2009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
American Advertising Federation. Raleigh-Durham
RL.00004
3.5 Linear Feet
Advertising trade association local chapter. Materials from the ADDY awards, organization bylaws and treasury reports, public service campaign materials, and other ephemera.
500 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In addition, original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Technical Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The American Advertising Federation Raleigh-Durham Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2007, 2008, and 2010.
Historical Note
The American Advertising Federation's Raleigh-Durham chapter is a non-profit trade organization for the advertising industry in the Triangle area (Raleigh, Durham, Chapel Hill) of North Carolina. It is one of several clubs in the AAF's Third District, and participates at the AAF's national level. The AAF-RDU works to connect the local advertising community through its conferences, panels, scholarships, mentorship, and fundraisers. It also conducts local ADDY Awards, which honor excellence and creativity in advertising. Winners of the AAF-RDU ADDYs advance to national ADDYs.
Collection Overview
The activities of the AAF-RDU chapter are represented by two main series, with some inevitable overlap between each group. Administrative records, ADDY competition events and entries, annual reports, and general correspondence are included in the Administrative Materials series. This series includes Accession (2007-0183) and Accession (2008-0125). Accession (2007-0183) includes three binders that detail the activities of the AAF-RDU from 2006-2007. It contains the organization's 2007 annual report, as well as materials from the chapter's public service campaign for the Interfaith Food Shuttle. Accession (2008-0125) includes a broad range of materials from the chapter's ADDY competition, beginning with ADDY event and preparation materials from 2003 and ending with ADDY programs and pamphlets from 2009. Also included are treasurer reports, board meetings, and by-law revisions from 2008-2009. There are also entry forms for the chapter's public service and advertising education ADDY entries from 2008, and some miscellaneous Silver Medal materials, dating 2004-2009. This accession includes several audiovisual materials, including Betacam SPs and DVDs, covering ADDY and Silver Medal awards shows. Also contained in this accession are ephemera from various AAF-RDU events, including two miniature billboards, one oversized ADDY poster, Club Achievement Awards plaques (dating from 1988-1993), crystal awards, and two trophies.
The second series in this collection deals exclusively with the club's public service campaigns, an annual project sponsored by AAF-RDU that involves local advertising students in creating a PSA for a local organization or charity. The Public Service Campaigns series includes Accession (2010-0105), which has records dating from 2004-2008 detailing the application process for both the organizations and the students interested in participating; the development of the campaign; and the final deliverables for each year's project.
Trade associations -- United States; Professional associations -- United States; Advertising; Advertising, Public service; Wake Enterprises; Me Fine Foundation; American Advertising Federation. Raleigh-Durham; American Advertising Federation -- Raleigh Durham; Inter-faith Food Shuttle; Haven House
- Administrative Materials, 2003-2009, 4 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Accession (2007-0183) contains three binders that detail activities in 2006-2007 including the 2007 report and their public service campaign for the Inter-faith Food Shuttle.
  Accession (2008-0125) (1.5 lin. ft.; 400 items; dated 2003-2009) includes materials from the ADDY awards, bylaws, budgets, and other ephemera including a poster, model billboards, trophies, plaques, and crystal awards.
  - Accession (2007-0183) (Box 1)
    - Binders, 2006-2007 (Box 1)
  - Accession (2008-0125) (Box 2)
    - ADDY preparations, 2004 (3 folders) (Box 2)
    - ADDY materials, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Third District Leadership conference, 2005 (Box 2)
    - ADDY materials, 2006 (Box 2)
    - Ad Club board meetings, 2007 (Box 2)
    - ADDY materials, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Advertising Education entry form, 2007-2008 (Box 2)
    - Public Service entry form, 2007-2008 (Box 2)
    - ADDY materials, 2008 (Box 2)
    - By-laws, budgets, etc., 2008-2009 (Box 2)
    - ADDY materials, 2009 (Box 2)
    - Silver Medal, 2004-2009 (Box 2)
    - Audiovisual materials
      - RBW Michael Winslow tribute, 2008 (Box 2)
      - ADDYs program, no date (Box 2)
      - ADDYs logo loop, no date (Box 2)
      - ADDYS, 2003-2009 and no date (6 DVDs) (Box 2)
      - Silver Medal, 2009 (Box 2)
      - Logos (loop), no date (Box 2)
    - Ephemera
      - Billboard model from ADDYs, 2008 (Box 2)
      - 2 sample ADDY crystal awards, 2006 and 2007 (Box 2)
      - 2 trophies for Silver and Gold ADDY (Box 2)
      - 1 plaque, 2008 (Box 2)
      - 1 plastic billboard for Fairway Co. (Box 2)
    - Club Achievement Award plaques, 1988-1993 (Box 3)
    - ADDY poster, 2006 (Oversize-folder 1)
- Public Service Campaigns, 2004-2008, 2 boxes
  Accession (2010-0105) includes binders and other materials from the AAF-RDU's annual public service campaign project. Materials detail the application process for both the nonprofit organizations and the students interested in participating in the advertising campaign; the development of the campaign; and the final deliverables for each year's project.
  - Haven House, 2004-2005 (4 folders) (Box 4)
  - Interfaith Food Shuttle, 2006 (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Me Fine Foundation, 2007 (2 of 4 folders) (Box 4)
  - Me Fine Foundation, 2007 (2 of 4 folders) (Box 5)
  - Wake Enterprises, 2008 (4 folders) (Box 5)